One Last Adventure: The Making of Stranger Things 5 is a
documentary film directed by Martina Radwan.
An inside look at the years of effort and craft that went into the final
installment of the Duffer Brothers' generation-defining series.
Self - Creator / Writer / Director, played by Ross Duffer.
Self - Creator / Writer / Director, played by Matt Duffer.
Self - Writer, played by Paul Dichter.
Self - Writer, played by Kate Trefry.
Self - Writer, played by Caitlin Schneiderhan.
Self - Executive Producer / Director / Guest Director
Chapter 6 And 7, played by Shawn Levy.
The fifth and final season of the American science fiction horror drama television series Stranger Things, marketed
as Stranger Things 5, was released on the streaming service Netflix in two volumes and the finale.
The first set of four episodes was released on November 26, 2025, the second set of three
episodes was released on December 25, and the finale was released on December 31.
It was produced by the show's creators, the Duffer
Brothers, along with Shawn Levy and Dan Cohen.
The season stars Winona Ryder, David Harbour, Millie Bobby Brown, Finn Wolfhard, Gaten Matarazzo, Caleb McLaughlin, Noah Schnapp, Sadie Sink, Natalia
Dyer, Charlie Heaton, Joe Keery, Maya Hawke, Brett Gelman, Priah Ferguson, Linda Hamilton, Cara Buono, Jamie Campbell Bower, and Nell Fisher.
Joe Chrest, Sherman Augustus, Alex Breaux, Jake Connelly, Amybeth McNulty,
Randy Havens, and Linnea Berthelsen appear in recurring roles.
The season received  positive reviews from critics.
However, audience reception to the season was more divisive with the
series certfied a rotten by audiences on Rotten Tomatoes.
The dissatisfactiion from some fans with how the series as whole concluded lead to internet theories that secret ninth episode pf the season
would be released with an an alternate " real" ending - these theories were dubbed "Conformity Gate" and would prove unfounded.
The film explores themes of friendship, melancholy,
behind the scenes, growing up, filmmaking.
The tone is emotional.